Welcome to our lecture on Docker
Docker is a platform designed to make it easier to create
deploy
and run applications by using containers
Containers allow developers to package up an application with all parts it needs
such as libraries and other dependencies
and ship it all out as one package
Today
we'll explore how Docker improves the software development lifecycle
optimizes resource management
and simplifies application deployment
By isolating applications in containers
Docker ensures consistent environments from development to production
This introduction will lay the foundation for understanding how Docker revolutionizes modern IT infrastructure