Docker is a powerful platform enabling developers to automate application deployment
scaling
and management using containerization
Containers package an application and its dependencies into a standardized unit for software development
ensuring it runs seamlessly across various computing environments
This technology has revolutionized the DevOps landscape
offering a consistent framework for both development and production environments
Understanding Docker's architecture
including images
containers
volumes
and networks
is crucial for leveraging its full potential in continuous integration and deployment setups