Docker is a platform for developing
shipping
and running applications inside containers
Containers are lightweight
executable
isolated environments that include everything needed to run an application
such as code
runtime
libraries
and system tools
This approach ensures consistency across different environments
from development to production
and helps to streamline the software development lifecycle by minimizing 'works on my machine' issues
Docker containers can be created and managed using the Docker Engine
which is available for Linux
Windows
and MacOS
Key features of Docker include image versioning
automated build processes
and the ability to share containerized applications through Docker Hub
a cloud-based registry service