In this lecture
we will introduce Docker
a platform designed to simplify application development and deployment by using containerization
Docker allows developers to package applications along with their dependencies into containers
ensuring consistency across multiple environments
A Docker container is a lightweight
standalone
and executable package that incorporates everything needed to run a piece of software
including the application code
runtime
system tools
and libraries
This characteristic makes it an essential tool for modern DevOps practices
enabling seamless collaboration between development and operations teams