In this lecture
we will explore the basics of Docker
a platform used for developing
shipping
and running applications in containers
A Docker container is a lightweight
standalone
executable package that includes everything needed to run a piece of software
such as the code
runtime
system tools
libraries
and settings
Using Docker
developers can streamline their workflows
ensuring that applications work seamlessly in various environments from development to production
This introduction will cover core Docker concepts
including images
containers
the Docker architecture
and how these elements fit together to facilitate application deployment