In this lecture on Docker
we will explore the core concepts and architecture of Docker
an essential tool for modern software development and deployment
Docker is a platform designed to facilitate the creation
deployment
and execution of applications using containers
Containers provide a lightweight and efficient alternative to traditional virtual machines
allowing developers to package an application with all its dependencies into a standardized unit for software development
The lecture will cover how Docker streamlines the development process
enhances collaboration
and simplifies the deployment of applications across different environments