Welcome to the world of Docker
where we streamline the process of deploying and managing applications in containers
Unlike traditional VM  Virtual Machine  approaches that require significant resources
Docker provides a lightweight and portable solution
enabling developers to package applications and dependencies cyclically
Imagine running your application comfortably in a consistent environment across different machines
from development to production
making collaborations and deployments efficient
In this introductory scene
we'll get a high-level overview of Docker's core concepts including Docker Image
Docker Container
and the Docker Engine