Docker is a platform that allows developers to automate the deployment of applications inside lightweight
portable containers
These containers can run virtually anywhere
whether on a developer's local machine
a data center
or in the cloud
Docker containers package an application with all its dependencies
ensuring consistency across various environments
This encapsulation simplifies software delivery by isolating applications from infrastructure
which addresses the common issue of 'works on my machine'
Docker's architecture includes a daemon that manages containers
images
and networks
alongside a client utility to issue commands