Docker is a platform designed to make it easier for developers to create
deploy
and run applications by using containers
Containers allow a developer to package up an application with all parts it needs
such as libraries and other dependencies
and ship it all out as one package
By doing so
the developer can be assured that the application will run on any other Linux machine regardless of any customized settings that machine might have that could differ from the machine used for writing and testing the code
With Docker
engineers can easily manage those tasks with fewer interruptions
ensuring their applications perform consistently